加油  凯特  别死在我面前
Come on, Kate. Don't you die on me.
坚持住  坚持住
Stay with me. Stay with me.
-左胸一处枪伤  -别死
- Single G.S.W. to left chest. - Do not die.
-加油  姑娘  -准备胸管  一级外伤
- Come on, girl. Come on. - Set up for a chest tube. Trauma one.
-交换  我们来吧  -这是我朋友
- Switch. We got this. - This is my friend.
你懂吗  她是我朋友
You understand me? She's my friend.
那就让我们救她
Then let us save her life.
31岁女性  左胸一处枪伤
31-year-old female. G.S.W. to the left chest.
路上已经昏迷
Crashed on the way in.
手术室已经准备好  医生正在赶过来
Trauma room is prepped. Trauma team's on the way.
好的  停止摁压
Okay, stop compressions.
有脉搏  检查呼吸
We have a rhythm. Let's check for breathing.
我们需要第二条线
We need a second line.
凯特
Kate.
她的呼吸微弱  把她抬到床上
Uh, her breathing is shallow. Let's get her on the table.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
呼叫科瓦克医生  通知他接手
Page Dr. Kovaks. Tell him he has to take over.
她是谁
Who is she?
她是我女朋友
She's my girlfriend.
你说找不到他是什么意思
What do you mean, you couldn't find him?
-有两百多个警察在那里  -我要所有进出口
- We had over 200 cops there. - I want security checkpoints...
都设立安检关卡
at all entrances and exits.
不  他不会凭空消失
No, he didn't just disappear.
十条街区以内有任何
If there's any surveillance cameras
-监控摄像机  -妈的
- within ten blocks of that place... - Damn it.
一小时之内
I want that footage
-给我录像带  -给每个人录口供
- on my desk in an hour. - I want statements from everyone.
不行  一个小时
No. One hour!
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
她怎么样了
How is she?
他们把她送进手术室了  但是
They just took her to surgery, but...
我们需要胸管
We need a chest tube.
高压86  低压60
B.P.'s 86 over 60.
胸管在哪
Where's that chest tube?
身后
Behind you.
加油  凯特  加油  坚持住
Come on, Kate. Come on. Stay with me.
坚持住  凯特  有我在
Stay with me, Kate. I've got you.
该死  左胸有出血
Damn it! Bleeding in the left chest.
-血氧含量88  -血气胸状况好转
- SATs are 88. - Tension pneumo's relieved,
但是她还在衰弱
but she's still decreased.
好了  我们不能等了  准备插管
Okay, we can't wait. Set up for intubation.
你不能给她动手术  她是你女朋友
You can't operate on her. She's your girlfriend.
她要死了  我不能等了
She's dying. I'm not waiting.
你参加葬礼去了  凯特
You were at a funeral, Kate.
怎么就中弹了
How the hell did you get shot?
凶手找到了吗
What about the shooter?
-跑了  -跑了  他怎么会跑了
- Gone. - Gone? How can he be gone?
不知道  但他把枪留下了
We don't know, but he left his weapon behind.
是马克11改良狙击步抢
It's a Mark 11 modified sniper rifle,
特种部队的惯用抢  我们正在找指纹
favorite of special forces. We're checking for prints now.
理查德
Richard.
-爸爸  -我的天
- Dad. - Oh, my God.
没事了  没事了
Shh. It's okay. It's okay.
爸爸
Dad.
凯特在哪
Where's Katie?
我女儿在哪
Where's my daughter?
血压  高压80  低压60
B.P.'s 80 over 60.
高压78  低压56
78 over 56.
出血太多了
There's too much blood.
你究竟哪里出血了  凯特
Where the hell are you bleeding from, Kate?
肺静脉  血管夹
Pulmonary vein. Clamp.
好了  找到你了  你这个混蛋
Okay. I got you, you son of a bitch.
-3-0缝合线  -血压还在下降
- 3-0 silk. - Blood pressure's still dropping.
-我尽快赶过来了  -31岁女性
- Got here as fast as I could. - 31-year-old female,
左胸一处枪伤
single G.S.W. to the chest.
好了  我来吧
It's okay, I got this.
左边血气胸状况缓和
Left tension pneumo alleviated,
胸管插入后  胸部有严重出血现象
a chest tube which revealed significant bleeding in the chest.
我说了  我来
I said, I got this.
出血处事左下肺部静脉
The bleeder was a left inferior pulmonary vein,
戴维森医生已经夹住了
which Dr. Davidson just clamped.
乔什  靠边
Josh, step aside.
我已经找到血管了  让我给她缝合
Already in. Just let me sew her up.
你做了你该做的
You did what you had to.
现在  按规矩走吧
Now... do what you're supposed to.
戴维森医生
Dr. Davidson.
缝合线
Suture.
3-0缝合线
3-0.
3-0在这儿
Here's the 3-0.
狙击手怎么出现在葬礼上
A sniper? At a funeral?
我们认为  那些人派人杀了蒙哥马利之后
We think the people who sent those guys after Montgomery
又把目标对准了贝克特
targeted Beckett.
我试图救她  我试着
I tried to get to her. I tried--
你以为你是谁
Hey! Oh! Who the hell do you think you--
-爸爸  爸爸  -是你干的  是你的错
- Dad! Dad! - You did this! This is your fault.
血压还在降低  血氧也是
B.P.'s still dropping. SATs are falling as well.
她身上一定还有别处在失血
She must be bleeding somewhere else.
在哪  血已经止住了
Where? There's no blood.
你促使她去调查她母亲的谋杀案
You pushed her to look into her mother's murder!
她因为你而中枪
She was shot because of you,
蒙哥马利的死也是因为你
and Montgomery is dead because of you!
别来烦他
Leave him alone!
-住手  -住手  你们俩  停下
- Stop it! - Stop it, all of you. Just stop it!
我女儿还在努力求生
I won't have you acting like 3 year olds
我不要看到你们像三岁的孩子似的
while my daughter's fighting for her life.
生命体征还在衰减
Vitals are still falling.
她的心包膜在膨胀
Her pericardium's distended.
她在内出血  所以没有血往外流
She's bleeding into it. That's why there's no blood.
血在压迫她的心脏  剪刀
It's compressing her heart. Scissors.
血压降低  高压65  低压45
B.P.'s dropping. 65/45.
好了
Got it.
子弹擦到了心室  3-0缝合线
Bullet grazed the ventricle. 3-0.
-她的心室纤维性颤抖  -电击板
- She's going into v-fib. - Paddles.
他说得对
He's right, you know?
这是我的错
This is my fault.
理查德·卡塞尔  不准你怪自己
Richard Castle, don't you dare blame yourself.
不是你枪杀的她
You are not the one who shot her.
电量到10
Charge to 10.
充好了
Charged.
准备就绪
Clear.
不
No.
但是我让她身处险境
But I put her in the crosshairs.
还在颤动  电量加到20
Still fibrillating. Charge to 20.
充电中
Charging.
我向她表露了心声
I told her how I felt.
我告诉她  我爱她
I told her I loved her.
准备就绪
Clear.
贝克特先生
Mr. Beckett?
是我
Yes.
你女儿已做完手术了
Your daughter is out of surgery.
她会没事吗
Will she be all right?
手术期间  她曾心脏骤停
Well, during the surgery, she experienced cardiac arrest.
我们让她的心脏自动重跳了
Now we were able to get her heart beating again on its own,
但是  我们需要密切观察她
But... we'll need to watch her very closely.
我什么时候能见她
When can I see her?
等护士把她安顿好
Well, once the nurses get her settled,
我们会带您去见她
we'll bring you back to her.
其余人该回家休息了
The rest of you should go home, get some rest.
我不知道你  兄弟
I don't know about you, bro,
但是我最不想的就是回家
but home is the last place I'm going.
等我们抓到那该死的凶手再说
Not till we catch the son of a bitch who did this.
我跟你一样
Right behind you.
我们没事  去吧
We're fine. Go.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
挺好
Yeah.
枪手的步枪
The shooter's rifle.
没有找到指纹
It's clean for prints.
实验室现在在寻找DNA的残留
Lab's running trace right now for D.N.A.
那枪呢  能追查到枪的来源吗
Well, what about the gun? Can we track the gun?
国防部称  该枪序列号对应的枪主
According to the D.O.D., the serial number matches a weapon
是一个叫马丁·霍斯特的人
that was issued to one Martin Holst,
7年前在一次行动中身亡的海豹突击队员
a Navy Seal who was killed in action seven years ago.
他的尸体在后来的行动中找到
His body was recovered in a subsequent mission,
但是武器丢了
but the weapon was not.
警犬科有何发现
Anything from the canine unit?
警犬嗅到一股气味
Dogs picked up a scent.
一路延续到墓地的西边
Traced it to the west side of the cemetery,
但之后就没有痕迹了
but then they lost it there.
在全是警察的地方  他怎么能不引起注意
In a sea of cops, how does this guy go unnoticed?
或许也不是没人看到
He may not have.
我们调查的半数的人称  记得看见过
Half the guys we talked to said they remember seeing
一名墓地管理员为躲避枪手  藏在一棵树后
a groundskeeper taking cover from the shooter behind a tree.
但墓园的工作人员说
But according to the grounds staff,
他们当时都不在那边
none of them were in the area.
他在骚乱中混入人群  然后消失了
He blended in during the chaos and then disappeared.
如果这人是受雇的职业杀手
If this guy's some pro for hire,
他现在很可能在逃往古巴的路上了
he could be halfway to cuba by now.
那我们就去古巴找他
Then we'll go to cuba and find his ass.
这说不通
It just doesn't make any sense.
这一切本该结束的
It was supposed to be over.
蒙哥马利牺牲了自己
Montgomery sacrificed himself.
杀了洛克伍德  和他的所有手下
Killing Lockwood and all of his guys,
他说了他会了结此事
he said he was ending it.
他说他这么做是为了保证她的安全
He said he was doing it to keep her safe.
如果目的是为了保护她
So if the plan was to keep her safe,
那他们为何还要来杀她
then why the hell are they still coming after her?
我不知道  伙计
I don't know, bro.
天知道还牵扯到别的什么人
God knows who else is involved.
我是卡塞尔
Castle.
是的  你确定吗
Yeah. Are you sure?
不  这手环你戴着好看
No, this bracelet looks good on you.
虽不是镶钻的
It's not diamonds.
嗨  卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
我查完房回来看你
I'll see you after rounds.
好啊
Yeah.
你盯着我  我看起来一定很糟糕
You're staring at me. I must look really bad.
不
No.
我只是没想到能再见到你
I just never thought I'd see you again.
我听说你这儿要开花店
I heard you were opening a flower store,
所以想做点贡献
so I thought I'd pitch in.
我醒来的时候  它们就在这儿
They were all here when I woke up.
我想大多是分局同事送的
I think they're mostly from the precinct.
真是丢大人了  卡塞尔
I don't think I'm gonna live this one down, Castle.
还好啦
Oh... probably not.
我听说你还试着救我
I hear that you tried to save me.
是啊  我...
Yeah, I, uh...
你听说
You heard?
你不记得我扑倒你吗
You don't remember me tackling you?
不  我不大记得了
No, I don't remember much of anything.
我记得我当时在台上
I, um, remember that I was on the podium.
之后的事都一片漆黑
And then I remember everything just going black.
你不记得
You don't remember...
枪击了
The gunshot?
不记得了
No.
常言道  有些事情
They say that there are some things
还是不记得为好
that are better not being remembered.
是啊
Yeah.
我总是想起他  卡塞尔
I keep seeing his face, Castle.
每当我闭上双眼
Every time I close my eyes,
就看到蒙哥马利躺在机库的地上
I see Montgomery lying on the hangar floor.
你应该让我去的
You shoulda let me go in there.
那他们就会杀了你
They would've killed you.
那可不一定
Oh, you don't know that.
-凯特  -卡塞尔
- Kate-- - Castle...
我现在
I'm really tired...
心神俱疲
right now.
是啊
Of course.
你说得对  我们明天再谈
Of course. We'll talk tomorrow.
我们可以不谈吗
Do you mind if we don't?
我只是需要一点时间
I just need a little bit of time.
没问题
Sure.
没问题  多久
Sure. How much time?
等我电话  好吗
I'll call you, okay?
好的
Sure.
美国国会大厦  请问您要转接哪里
United States Capitol. How may I direct your call?
国会办公室  谢谢
Congressional offices, please.
请稍等
Hold, please.
你好啊  贝克特  你在这里干什么
Hey, Beckett. What are you doing here?
我还以为你下周才回来呢
I didn't think you were back till next week.
整整两个月闷在我爸的小木屋里
Yeah, well, two months of listening to crickets
听山间虫鸣
in my dad's cabin...
要把我逼疯了
was driving me nuts.
没事的  你不用找理由
It's okay. You don't have to make excuses.
我们知道你想我们  所以才会回来
We know you missed us. That's why you couldn't stay away.
得了吧
Shut up.
怎么样  有什么发现
So? Anything?
依旧毫无进展
Still nowhere.
那个墓地管理员呢
Well, what about the groundskeeper?
那个人消失了
The guy's a ghost.
我们用监控录像找人  找车牌
We ran face hits on surveillance, license plates.
没查到东西
Nothing panned out.
我们倒是在凶器上提取到了DNA
We did get D.N.A. off the weapon,
但是系统中没有相匹配的
but there were no matches in the system.
不过我们做了标记
We flagged it, though.
这些卡塞尔都没告诉你吗
Uh, didn't Castle tell you about all this?
没有
No.
真奇怪  他为什么会向你隐瞒
That's weird. Why wouldn't he--why would he hide that from you?
他没有隐瞒什么  只是我有段时间没见他了
He's not hiding anything. I just haven't see him in a while.
有段时间是多久
How long is a while?
差不多就是枪击后吧
Pretty much since the shooting.
为什么  出什么事了
Why? What happened?
啥事没有  我只是需要时间休整
Nothing happened. I just needed some time.
怎么  他整整三个月对你不闻不问
What, he left you alone for three months?
行了  不是他的错
You guys, it wasn't his fault.
我跟他说等我电话
I told him that I would call.
那你为什么没打
Well, why didn't you?
他每天都来这里和我们一起查案
He was here with us every day, working the case,
查了好几个月
for months.
要不是新警监
He'd still be here
把他撵走了  他还会待在这
if the new captain hadn't kicked him to the curb.
她把他撵走了  为什么
She kicked him out? Why?
显然  她的分局
Apparently, uh, her precinct's
容不下一个半吊子作家
got no room for a dilettante writer
扮警察玩
playing cop.
维克多利亚·盖茨警监
Captain Victoria Gates,
绰号铁娘子盖茨
A.K.A. Iron Gates.
严格按照规章办事
As by-the-book as they come.
她是从内务处磨练出来的探长
She cut her teeth as a detective with Internal Affairs.
那可不是招人喜欢的差事
Wow. That's not gonna win her any popularity points.
是啊  她似乎把对警察的不信任也带来了
Yeah. It's like she brought her distrust of cops along with her.
至少可以确定一点  她与蒙哥马利不同
Well, one thing's for sure, she's no Montgomery.
她还没和卡塞尔谈过
Hey, she hasn't talked to Castle.
-她还不知道银行的事  -什么银行
- She doesn't know about the bank yet. - What bank?
反正我们追查枪手毫无进展
Uh, well, we weren't getting any traction with the shooter,
所以卡塞尔建议我们调查一下
so Castle suggested we check out
蒙哥马利  麦卡利斯特和拉格兰
Montgomery, Mccallister, and Raglan.
看看他们以前可能在和谁做交易
See who they might have been in business with back in the day.
我们知道他们是靠绑架黑帮成员牟利
We know those guys were getting fat ransoming wise guys.
或许他们用那个小金库
Maybe they used that stash
去支付谋杀你母亲的凶手的酬劳
to pay off the guy that ordered your mother's murder.
卡塞尔认为他找到了他们用过的银行
Yeah, so Castle thinks he found the bank they used.
这么说有条钱财线索
So there's a money trail.
唯一的问题是  银行倒闭了
The only problem is, the bank closed down.
没人知道那些历史记录在哪里
No one knows where those old records ended up.
我们正在设法寻找的时候
We were working to locate them
铁娘子盖茨叫停了调查
when iron Gates shut down the investigation.
什么  她叫停了调查  为什么
W--she shut the case down? Why?
没有枪手的新线索
No new leads on the shooter.
而且如果我们告诉她其他案情
And we couldn't tell her the rest of it
就必然会涉及到蒙哥马利警监
without implicating Captain Montgomery.
女士
Ma'am.
要是我妈过来拜访  你倒是可以叫她女士
If my mother drops by, you can call her ma'am.
叫我长官或者警监
Call me sir or Captain.
我是贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
我今天复职了
Back on active as of today.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
久闻大名
Your reputation precedes you.
纽约警局史上最年轻女探长
Youngest woman in the NYPD to make detective.
比我早了六周
You beat me by six weeks.
我没想到这都有记录
I didn't realize that people kept score.
人人心中有杆秤  探长
Everybody keeps score, detective,
特别是市局的人
especially those downtown.
看来你通过了心理评估
Looks like you passed your psych eval,
那么  欢迎回来
so, uh, welcome back.
谢谢  我还需要配枪
Thank you. Uh, I-I'll also need my gun.
等你重获资格了再给你
Not until you requalify.
您说什么
I'm sorry?
你离职了三个月
You were on disability for three months.
按照规定你只有重获资格了之后
Regs says you don't get your piece back
才能拿回配枪
until you requalify.
那我的案子怎么办  规定里有说吗
And what about my case? What do regs say about that?
三个月毫无线索
Three months and no leads,
而每天都有新的凶案发生
and every day, more homicides coming through that door?
你指望我让他们一直摸黑乱撞下去吗
How long did you expect me to let those folks tread water?
调查这案子的都是好手
There were good people on this case.
只是根本没有线索可挖
There just isn't anything out there--
抱歉  长官  恕我直言  我和他们不一样
I'm sorry, sir, but with all due respect, those people aren't me.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你派去调查这案子的警员  没有我的能力
The people that you had working this case, they're not me.
听着  我不知道蒙哥马利
Look, I don't know what kind of shop
在这里时什么作风
Montgomery was running here,
但我绝不会允许任何一个警察调查
but it'll be a cold day in hell if I let a cop--any cop--
自己被枪击的案件
investigate their own shooting.
我的分局不是报仇雪恨的地方
My precinct is no place for vendettas.
这回话说清楚了吗
Do we understand each other?
我想要回我的枪
I want my gun.
等重新审批合格呗
So you gotta requalify.
没什么大不了的  虽然是有些窝火
It's no big deal. It is a little insulting, but--
记录资金流动的那些文件在哪里
Where are the files on the money trail?
在卡塞尔那里
Castle's got 'em.
你想我们怎么办  莫非留在这里
What were we supposed to do, leave 'em here so...
好让盖茨发现吗
Gates could find 'em?
她肯定会第一时间对蒙哥马利展开调查
First thing she would do is open an investigation of Montgomery.
你想看文件  就得找他
You want to see the files, you're gonna have to talk to him.
不管你做什么  别被逮到
Whatever you do, don't get caught.
拜托  她能怎么样  派我去当交警吗
Oh, come on. What's she gonna do, bust me down to traffic?
比那还遭
Worse.
现在和以前不同了
It's not like it was before.
我们要是违了她的愿
We go against her orders on this,
就等着被炒鱿鱼吧
we could all lose our badges.
我是莱恩
Yeah, Ryan.
什么情况
Yeah, what do you got?
他是有些偏执  但他说得在理
He is paranoid... but right.
这样的话
Well, then...
那我最好别被逮到
I guess I better not get caught.
新案子  十八街和莱克斯交口
We got a fresh one. 18th and Lex.
你来吗
You coming?
不了  我留在这里好了
No. I think I'm gonna sit this one out.
她要是继续查下去  我们都会饭碗不保
If she keeps looking into this, we could all lose our jobs.
你怎么不想想她的生活
What about her life?
枪手依旧逍遥法外
The shooter's still out there.
她怎能坐以待毙
How's she supposed to live like that?
看来玩得很开心啊
Someone had a party.
被害人是索亚·吉伯特  27岁
Victim is Sonya Gilbert, 27.
这里是她家
This is her place.
索亚·吉伯特
Sonya Gilbert?
就是狗仔队最爱的那个交际花
As in paparazzi-favorite party girl?
胸部多次中枪
Multiple GSW to the chest.
凶手用这个枕头当简易消音器
The killer used the pillow as a poor-man's suppressor.
胸部中枪是吧
Gunshots to the chest, huh?
还好贝克特没来
Good thing Beckett sat this one out.
-贝克特归队了  -是的
- Beckett's back? - Yeah.
-她也没联系你吗  -好几周没信了
- She hasn't called you either? - Not for weeks.
被害人的妹妹几小时前发现的尸体
Victim's sister found her an hour ago.
她们本来约好了今天逛街
They were supposed to go shopping today.
警报系统在昨晚十点左右启动
Alarm system was activated around 10:00 last night,
那之前  有人看到被害人和其男友
right after the victim and her boyfriend
回到公寓
were seen returning home.
系统于今早九点才被解除
It wasn't deactivated till 9:00 am this morning.
有目击证人看见她男友在那之后离开
Boyfriend was spotted leaving the apartment right after that.
死亡时间
Time of death?
凌晨三到四点
Between 3:00 and 4:00 am.
这位男友叫什么名字
This boyfriend have a name?
被害人的妹妹说他叫戴尔·兰德斯
Vic's sister identified him as a Dale Landers.
"粒子方程"乐队的鼓手
Drummer from Particle Equation.
他们交往半年了
They've been dating for six months.
《人物》杂志上看到的  怎么了
"People" Magazine. What?
派人去他的已知地址  把通缉令发出去
Get a unit to his last known and get an APB out.
名媛遇害  男友是重金属乐队鼓手
Dead celebutante, heavy-metal drummer--
卡塞尔会喜欢这案子的
Castle would've loved this one.
你觉得贝克特会不会找新上司说说情
Hey, you think maybe Beckett can talk the new captain
叫他回来
into bringing him back?
她晾了他三个月
She left him hanging for three months.
你觉得他会愿意回来吗
What makes you think he's gonna want to come back?
你可真是我最喜欢的粉丝
Well, that makes you my favorite fan.
谢谢
Thanks.
真不敢相信我见到你真人了
I can't believe I'm meeting you right now.
你是我最爱的作家
You're my favorite author.
感谢你抽空前来
Thank you for coming out.
你好  你好
How are you? Hi there.
这是签给谁的  请问你叫什么
Who should I make it out to? And your name is?
你叫什么  当然可以
And your name is? Sure can.
你好  你好
How you doing? How are you?
感谢前来  你的名字是
Thanks for coming. And your name is?
这本签给谁
And who should I make it out to?
凯特
Kate.
这本签给凯特
You can make it out to kate.
非常感谢  你们都辛苦了
Thank you very much. Thank you very much for the hard work.
下次我再出书  一定还来这里
Next time I write a book, I'll be sure to come by.
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
卡塞尔  等一下
Castle, wait.
我等了  三个月  你根本没打电话
I did, three months. You never called.
我知道你很生气
Look, I know you're angry--
没错  我确实很生气
Oh, you're damn right I'm angry.
在救护车里我看着你奄奄一息
I watched you die in that ambulance.
你知道吗
Did you know that?
你知道那是怎样的感受吗
You know what that's like,
看着你在乎的人一步步
watching the life drain out of someone you...
离你远去
someone you care about?
我告诉过你  我需要点时间
I told you, I needed some time.
你当时说你需要几天
You said a few days.
几天并不够
Well, I needed more.
那你该说清楚
Well, you shoulda said that.
卡塞尔  我没法给你打电话
Castle, look, I couldn't call you.
打了电话  我定会陷入...
Okay? Not without dragging myself into...
我想要暂时远离的所有这一切
everything that I was just trying to get some space from.
我需要时间理清思路调整一下
I needed some time to just work through everything.
乔什有陪着你吗
Josh help you with that?
我们分手了
We broke up.
我喜欢这题词
I like the dedication.
感觉那很合适
It seemed right.
写那结局的时候一定很难吧
It must have been hard, writing that ending.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
出了这么多状况  是啊
Given the circumstances, yeah.
你们为什么分手
So why'd you guys break up?
我真的很喜欢他
I really, really liked him.
但喜欢还不够
But that wasn't enough.
我妈妈遇害以后
After my mother was killed,
我内心有些东西就变了
something inside me changed.
我好像是筑起了一堵心墙
It's like I built up this wall inside.
我不知道  也许是不想再次伤得那么痛
I don't know. I guess I just didn't want to hurt like that again.
我知道我成不了
I know I'm not gonna be able to be
我想要成为的那种人
the kind of person that I want to be,
我知道我无法
I know I'm not gonna...
无法获得想要的那种感情
I'm not gonna be able to have the kind of relationship that I want...
除非这堵心墙倒塌
until that wall comes down.
这事不解决
And it's not gonna happen
我的心结无法解开
till I put this thing to rest.
那么我想我们必须要...
Well, then I suppose we're just gonna have to...
把这些家伙找出来  把他们解决掉
find these guys and take 'em down.
这不代表我不生气了
That doesn't mean I'm not still mad.
他俩跟我说了你做的那些事
The boys told me about what you did,
从钱的线索下手
following the money trail,
试着查出他们把钱转给了谁
trying to track down who the cops paid off.
我只是希望找到突破口
I just wish it led somewhere.
我查到了那些文件  银行倒闭的时候
I mean, I located their files. When the bank closed,
他们把那些死账的文件都拿走了
they took all the dead account paperwork
存放在尤宁城的一间仓库里
and stored it in a warehouse in Union City,
但在搬迁的几年后
but a couple years after the move,
一场大火把所有文件都烧了
a fire broke out, and the files were destroyed.
又是死胡同一条
It's just another dead end.
是怎么起火的
How'd it happen?
那场意外  电线老化
It was an accident. It was old wiring.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是的  有过调查的
Yeah, there was an investigation.
你看过火灾调查员的报告了吗
Well, did you see the report from the fire investigator?
没  但是...
No, but...
不是吧  蓄意烧掉仓库
Really, a warehouse fire?
为了区区几份文件也太大动干戈了吧
Seems an awful lot of trouble just for a couple of files.
比起他们之前所作所为  这也算不了什么
That's no more trouble than they've already gone through.
我们一定得看看那报告
I mean, we have to read that report.
但还有一个问题
It's just, there's this one problem.
什么
What?
盖茨都把你轰走了  你还怎么帮忙啊
How are you gonna help if Gates kicked you out?
我之所以任由她轰我走
I only let her kick me out
是因为我没必要留下来
because there was no reason to stay.
她会把我招回去的
She'll take me back.
我要卡塞尔回局里
And I want Castle back at the precinct.
是的  市长先生
Yes, Mr. Mayor.
是的  先生  我明白
Yes, Sir. I understand.
就今天  没得商量
Today. No more discussion.
好吧  我...
Okay. I--
卡塞尔先生  越级搞小动作
You think you're clever, Mr. Castle,
还觉得自己很聪明  是吗
going around my back like that?
不过我告诉你
Well, let me tell you the score,
不管你的朋友有多么位高权重
I don't care how powerful your friends are,
你要是在我眼皮底下把事情搞砸了
you screw up at all on my watch,
我会以法律的最大限度去起诉你
and I'll prosecute you to the fullest extent of the law.
-你明白了吗  -是的  女士
- You understand me? - Yes, ma'am.
-长官  -长官
- Sir. - Sir.
立马从我办公室消失
Now get out of my office.
探长
Detective.
在
Yes.
如果你
You...
或刚才那位老兄
or that pal there
再让我下不了台
embarrass me like that again,
我会灭了你们
I will bury you.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
还有件事
Now, um,
如果您不介意
if you don't mind...
我希望能把配枪取回
I'd like my gun back.
利用市长让她丢脸
Showing her up with the Mayor?
你这样简直就是捅蜂窝啊
You might as well have beaten a beehive with a bat.
但事情搞定了  不是吗
Well, it worked, didn't it?
再说  看到她的脸
Besides, it sure was great
扭曲成那样  很给力啊
seeing her face twitch like that.
索亚·吉伯特
Sonya Gilbert?
是的  枪支  毒品  爱情变质
Yep. Guns, drugs, and love gone wrong.
她的男朋友哪儿去了
Where are you with the boyfriend?
已经发了全面通缉  但他还没回过家
APB's out, but he hasn't been home,
他的乐队成员也都不知道他在哪儿
and none of his bandmates know where he is.
他的动机是什么
What was his motive?
再普通不过  他和被害人起了争执
The usual. He and the vic had been fighting.
他爱得发狂  她却激情不再
He was in love, she wanted out.
我把火灾报告从记录里调了出来
I pulled the report on the fire from records.
你看日期
Check the date.
仓库是在我妈妈被谋杀三周后被烧毁的
That warehouse burned down three weeks after my mom's murder.
那一定不是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
有人在毁灭证据
Someone was destroying evidence.
那些能查出谁杀害了你妈妈的证据
Evidence that could lead to your mom's killers.
但调查员把它划为意外事故
But the investigator ruled it an accident.
而且没有任何迹象表明是纵火
And there's nothing in there to suggest arson.
也许有人篡改了报告
Maybe someone altered it.
有个简单的办法能查出真相
There's an easy way to find out.
去问问那个写报告的罗德·豪斯德就行了
Just ask the man who wrote the report, Rod Halstead.
除非他们把他也杀了
Unless they got to him, too.
不  他活着  还在职呢
No. He's alive and on the job.
你俩现在快去找他  查出有料线索
Now get your ass over there and find something
好让我们重开案件
we can use to reopen the investigation.
莱恩  埃斯波西托
Ryan! Esposito!
在  我俩只是...
Yeah, we were just...
是啊  我俩只是倒杯水喝
Yeah, we were just getting a drink of water.
是啊  饮水机是不是坏了  我只是...
Yeah, is that thing broken? I just--
准备出动
Saddle up.
全面通缉有消息了
We just got a hit on the APB.
一个巡警认出了索亚·吉伯特的男友
A beat cop IDed Sonya Gilbert's boyfriend.
他刚刚进入下东区
Heading into the band's rehearsal garage
乐队排练的车库  你也要去  贝克特
on the lower east side. You, too, Beckett!
把这藏好
Hide this.
你行吗
Hey, you ready for this?
你说笑呢吧
You're kidding, right?
好吧  但我们打前锋
Okay. But we got point.
走吧
Let's go.
你来这儿是脑袋进水了吗  戴尔
What the hell were you thinking, coming here, Dale, huh?
求你了  兄弟  我只是需要一点钱出城
Please, bro! I just need some money to get outta town.
纽约警察
NYPD!
纽约警察  立刻把手举起来
NYPD! Let me see your hands right now!
把手举起来  蹲下
Let me see 'em! Down!
-让我看见你的手  -兰德斯  别那样做
- Let me see 'em! Show me-- - Landers, don't do it!
-站住  -举起手来  快点
- Stop! - Put 'em in the air. Come on!
给我趴下
Get on the ground.
不
No.
把枪放下  不然我就开枪了  快放下
Drop it or I'll drop you! Drop it now!
好吧好吧
Okay, okay, okay!
马上放下  趴下
Drop it right now! On the ground!
快趴下  趴下
Get on the ground! Down! Down!
别动
Don't move.
与杀死索亚·吉伯特的枪口径相同
The same caliber that killed Sonya Gilbert.
那不是我的枪  哥们
Hey, it's not my gun, man.
我发誓  那不是我的枪
I swear. It's not my gun.
你给我坐老实了
Sit your ass down in that chair.
先说说你为什么要逃跑吧
Why don't we start with why you ran?
或是说说你为什么拿枪指着一名警官
Or maybe why you were pointing a gun at a police officer.
-再或者...  -你想谈谈吗
- Or maybe... - You want to talk about it?
-谈什么  -凯特  我都看见了
- About what? - Kate, I saw you.
那晚发生了什么事
So what happened that night?
看到那把枪的时候  你愣住了
When you saw that gun, you froze.
没什么
It's nothing.
你的手在发抖  那不是小事
Your hand was shaking. That's not nothing.
卡塞尔  我才归队两天
Castle, it's my second day back.
没什么大不了的
That's all. It's no big deal.
-如果再次发生怎么办  -不会的
- And if it happens again? - It won't.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
找出谁烧掉了仓库
Find out who burned down that warehouse.
找出杀我妈妈的凶手
Find out who killed my mom.
得了  戴尔  我们都知道是你杀了她
Come on, Dale. We know you killed her.
告诉我们动机
Just tell us why,
我们会跟地方检察官求情说你很合作
and we'll tell the D.A. that you cooperated.
戴尔  你的枪就是凶器
The gun's a match, Dale.
告诉过你们  那枪不是我的
I told you, it's not mine.
那为什么会在你手上
Then why were you holding it?
我们有目击证人看见你进入了她的公寓
We have witnesses who saw you enter her apartment
随后离开
and then leave.
没错  我是去过
Yeah, that's right. I-I was there, okay?
然后
And then...
我也不知道  我睡过去了
Look, man, I-I don't know. I-I-I crashed.
当我醒来的时候  那里都是血
And when I woke up, there was all this blood
枪不知道怎么就在我手里了
and--and this was in my hand.
你是什么意思  戴尔
So what are you saying, Dale,
你睡着的时候杀了她吗
you sleep shot her?
这就是你的辩词吗
Is that your defense?
不是
No.
我是说  不是我干的
Look, I--I'm saying, it wasn't me.
就是说  你睡着了
So... you went to bed
女友被杀你都没被吵醒吗
and you slept through your girlfriend's murder?
六枪都没叫醒你吗
Six shots?
你一定睡得很沉
You must be a heavy sleeper.
作案动机  时机  持有凶器
Motive, opportunity, possession of the weapon--
谋杀三要素被他全中
Looks like a murder-one trifecta.
他的乐队成员  米奇·扬希
His bandmate, Mitch Yancey there,
说戴尔需要钱
said he was looking for
-出城  -我不知道
- some money to get out of town. - I don't know...
好的  联系地方检察官
All right, contact the D.A.'s office.
正式落案起诉  通知他家人
Have them file charges, and let the family know.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
卡塞尔和贝克特去哪了
Where did Castle and Beckett go off to?
他们
They, uh...
他们去查另一条线索了
They had another lead they were looking into.
另一条线索
Another lead?
你们已经抓到犯人了
You caught the guy.
是的  他们去复查目击证人的供词
Yeah, they were double-checking eyewitness accounts.
因为这个案子很受瞩目
Since it's a high-profile case,
贝克特要保证这个案子没有一丝错误
Beckett wants to make sure that we don't make any mistakes.
我真欣慰啊  因为我们都不希望
Well, that's good to hear, 'cause we wouldn't want her
她犯下任何错误  不是吗
making any mistakes, now would we?
尤宁城的仓库
Warehouse in Union City?
我记得那场火灾
Yeah, yeah, I remember this fire.
报告说这是一起意外事故
The report said it was an accident.
是的  没错
Yeah, that's right.
-你确定吗  -我确定
- And you're sure? - Yeah, I'm sure.
这份文件自被存档以后
And this report hasn't been altered in any way
有没有被涂改过呢
since you filed it?
没有  怎么这么问
No. Why?
豪斯德先生  这点至关重要
Mr. Halstead, this is very important.
有没有什么你没写进报告的内容呢
Was there anything that you didn't put in that report?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
有没有迹象表明这是可疑的行为
Anything that might indicate suspicious activity.
如果有任何可疑的迹象
Well, if there was anything suspicious,
报告里一定会有的  探长
Detective, it'd be in the report.
接线盒功率骤增
Power surge to the junction box--
难得一见的事故
one-in-a-million event.
谢谢
Thanks.
就是说绝对没有人胁迫你
So at no point did anyone pressure you
在报告中遗漏什么  是吗
into keeping some information out of that report?
你可是越界了
You are way outta line here.
我越界吗  我可没有篡改报告
I'm out of line? I'm not the one who falsified that report.
-贝克特  -滚出我的消防站
- Beckett-- - Get out of my station.
是谁放的火  是谁让你掩盖罪行
Who set that fire? Who had you cover it up?
-滚  -好了
- Get out! - Okay.
告诉他们  我不会就此罢休
You tell them that I'm coming after them!
告诉他们  我一定会找到他们
And you tell them that I'll find them!
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
他在说谎
He's lying.
你可不知道
You don't know that.
我知道
Yes, I do.
埃斯波西托
Esposito.
我要你给我关于罗德·豪斯德的所有资料
I need you to get me everything you can on Rod Halstead.
是的  资料送到我公寓去
Yeah, and send it to my apartment.
我可不想被盖茨发现
I don't need Gates looking over my shoulder.
懂了
You got it.
贝克特打来的
That was Beckett.
豪斯德那边查得如何
How'd it go with Halstead?
她要我拿些资料给她  达成协议了吗
She wants to pull some files. He cut a deal yet?
没呢
Nope.
知道我哪里想不通吗
You know what I don't get?
什么
What's that?
我们掌握的死亡时间是凌晨3点
Our time of death is around 3:00 a.m.
如果戴尔是凶手的话
Now if Dale's our shooter,
为什么他杀死索亚之后
why'd he hang around for another six hours
还要再逗留6个小时呢
after he shot Sonya?
喜欢抱抱咯
Likes to cuddle.
我也不知道  杀掉自己的女友
I don't know. It's not like blowing away your girlfriend
又不是正常的行为
is a rational act to begin with.
为什么这么问
Why?
如果我有疑问  陪审团也会有
If I'm asking the question, the jury's gonna be, too.
这个家伙因为英勇而受过多次表彰
This guy's got multiple citations for valor,
还受到过市长的赞赏
commendations from the Mayor,
他多次将市民从着火的大楼中救出
he's literally saved dozens of people from burning buildings.
很难相信这个人有污点
It's hard to believe this guy's dirty.
但我们之前有过这样的惊诧
Yeah. Well, we've been surprised before.
好吧
Okay.
他和这案子中的其他人有过交集吗
Does he intersect with anyone else in the case--
蒙哥马利  拉格兰  麦卡利斯特
un, Montgomery, Raglan, McCallister?
没有  档案里没有提及
No, there's nothing in the files.
也许他们是私下认识
Might have known them socially.
但我们仔仔细细地查过了他们的生活
But we've been over their lives with a fine-tooth comb.
他一次也没出现过
He's never come up once.
好吧  也许他是个利用对象
Okay, so maybe he was a target of opportunity.
他可能急需用钱
He might have needed the money.
他的财务记录显示他没有这种状况
Nothing in his financial records to indicate any problems,
而考虑到他的记录  他
and given his record, he's...
考虑到他的记录  怎么了
Given his record, what?
其实我想说  如果他不是我们要找的人呢
I'm just saying, what if he's not our guy?
如果那场火灾是意外呢
What if the fire was an accident?
那不是一场意外  我知道肯定不是
It wasn't an accident. I know it wasn't an accident.
-你没法如此确定  -我很确定
- You can't know that. - I can,
因为如果这是场意外
because if this was an accident,
那我又将毫无头绪
then I've got nowhere to start.
若是场意外  就什么线索都没有了
If this was an accident, then I've got nothing.
狙击我的那人消失了
The guy who shot me is gone.
迪克·库南  死了
Dick Coonan--gone.
哈尔·洛克伍德  死了
Hal Lockwood--gone.
蒙哥马利  也死了
Montgomery--gone.
我的母亲  所有人都不在了  卡塞尔
My mom-- everybody is gone, Castle.
你今天没回来吃晚饭
Missed you for dinner tonight.
我知道  不好意思  我在工作
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry. I was working.
你和贝克特在一起
You were with Beckett.
是的
Yeah.
你不是说不再回去了吗
I thought you said you weren't going back.
是啊
I'm not.
听着  我不会回去  只办这个案子
Look, I'm not. It's just this one case.
随你  冰箱里有剩饭
Yeah, well, there's leftovers in the fridge.
你好
Hello.
-卡塞尔先生吗  -是的
- Mr. Castle. - Yeah.
我是罗伊·蒙哥马利的朋友
I'm a friend of Roy Montgomery's.
我打电话来是为了贝克特探长
I'm calling about Detective Beckett.
我们要谈一谈
We need to talk.
你知道他是谁吗
Do you have any idea who he was?
只知道他是蒙哥马利的朋友
Just that he's a friend of Montgomery's,
说蒙哥马利救了他一命
That he owed Montgomery his life.
还说蒙哥马利把一些文件寄给了他
He said Montgomery sent him some files--
那些文件一旦泄漏出去
files that, if they ever got out,
能把一批大人物拉下马
could hurt some very powerful people.
他们以这些文件作为威胁
They were using those files as a threat
防止蒙哥马利的家人受到伤害
to keep Montgomery's family from every being harmed.
保证贝克特的安全也是协议的一部分
Beckett's safety was also part of the deal.
但他们还是对她下手了啊
But they went after her anyway.
他是在她被枪击后才收到文件的
He didn't get the files until after she was shot.
他说她现在是安全的
He says she's safe now...
不过有个条件
on one condition.
她不再碰这个案子
She can't go near the case.
否则他也没法保证她的安全
If she does, he can't guarantee her safety.
若她穷追不舍  他们会杀了她
If she digs, they will kill her.
这个人  你相信他吗
And this man, you believe him?
-我相信  -那你得告诉她
- I do. - Then you have to tell her.
若我坦白  她肯定会不顾一切
If I do that, she'll put on blinders
奋不顾身地去一探究竟
and run out into the line of fire.
我不能让她这么干
I can't let that happen.
你没有办法改变她  理查德
You are not going to change her, Richard.
她会继续研究这个案子
She's gonna keep going out there
试图找出真相
and she's gonna keep digging.
除非我说服她
Not if stop her.
她会听我的
She'll listen to me.
我可以转移她的注意力
I can steer her away.
你能撑多久
For how long?
我不会再让她陷入险境
I'm not gonna lose her again.
我猜不仅仅是这个案子  是吧
So I guess it's not just for this case, is it?
你听到了多少
How much did you hear?
该听的都听了
Enough.
你一个字都不能透露出去
Look, it's really important you don't say anything.
知道吗  尤其不能告诉贝克特
All right? Especially to Beckett.
你的态度好像是一切都为了她
You act like this is all about her,
但你就在她旁边
but you were standing right next to her.
被击中的可能是你  老天  也可能是我
You could've been shot. Hell, I could've been shot.
所以我才要这么做  让他们远离我们
That's why I have to do this, to make sure they stay away.
真的吗
Yeah?
成熟点吧  老爸
You need to grow up, Dad.
你是作家  不是警察
You're a writer, not a cop.
别再假扮了
Stop pretending.
谢谢
Thanks.
你还记得
Do you remember
我第一次提起你母亲的案子时
what you told me the first time
你对我说了什么吗
I brought up your mother's case?
说你一旦开始  就停不下来
That if you got started again, you wouldn't stop.
说这个案子可能会毁了你
You said it would probably destroy you.
是啊  可我当时没有任何线索
Yeah, well, I didn't have any leads then.
我们现在也没有
We don't have any now.
听着  卡塞尔
Look, Castle,
我昨晚有些太激动了
I got a little emotional last night.
我...
I'm...
我没事
I'm fine.
不  你不好
No, you're not.
你自己也清楚这一点
And you know you're not.
你回警局三天
You've been back here three days.
就已经失控了
You're already in a freefall.
我不是让你彻底放手
I'm not telling you to walk away.
我是说...慢慢来
I'm just saying... give it time.
直到你冷静下来  恢复过来
You know, just until you get your bearings again.
有人想要杀我
How am I supposed to get my bearings
你让我怎么冷静
when someone out there wants me dead?
使自己不被他们困扰
By not letting them rob you of your life.
我向你保证
I promise you,
会有水落石出的一天
we will figure this out.
我们会逮到他们
We're gonna find them
并让他们付出应有的代价
and we're gonna make them pay.
但不是今日
Just not today.
卡塞尔  若放下这个案子  我会很迷茫
Castle, if I don't do this, I don't know who I am.
你还是以前的你
You're who you always were.
你尊重被害人
You're the one who honors the victims.
你能为索亚的家人
You're the one who can bring
抚平心灵的伤痛
Sonya's family some peace.
有何发现
Anything?
地方检察官说  本来铁板订钉的案子
According to the D.A., we just turned a slam-dunk case
现在没戏了
into a hail mary.
特警小莱恩不停调查
Yeah, super cop over here had to keep digging
-然后...  -然后什么
- so, you know... - And?
鉴证组在喝伏特加的杯子里
C.S.U. found trace residual of, uh, barbiturates
发现了巴比妥类药物
in the vodka glasses,
就是说戴尔和索亚在回到公寓后
which means Dale and Sonya were both roofied
都被灌了迷药
when they got back to the apartment.
但还有可能是男友干的  对吧
Well, it still could have been the boyfriend, right?
他本来想给她下药
I mean, he could've meant to roofie her,
却把自己也撂倒了  这么说也解释不了这案子
but roofied them both instead, not that that makes any sense.
但还能怎么解释呢
But what other explanation is there?
公寓里没有其他人
There was no one else in the apartment,
而且根据安保系统记录
and according to the security system,
在晚上十点到早上九点间
no one else entered or left the apartment
公寓没有人进出
between 10:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m.
就是说  死者男友肯定是凶手
Which means the boyfriend has to be the shooter.
除非
Unless...
除非什么
Unless what?
除非凶手一直都躲在屋里
The killer was in the apartment the whole time.
他们回家的时候
When they came home,
还以为家里没人
they thought they were alone.
与此同时  当他们不在屋里的时候
Meanwhile, while they're out of the room,
凶手就溜出来  在他们的酒里下药
the killer...slips out, spikes their drinks,
然后再偷偷溜回到他的藏身之地
and then slips back into his hiding place, where he...
凶手也可能是个女人
Or she...
静静地等着药效发作
waits for them to pass out.
真是守株待兔呀
Literally lying in wait.
真吓人
That's creepy.
几个小时以后
And then a couple of hours later,
他再溜出来  抓了个枕头
he slips out again, grabs the pillow,
-射杀被害人  然后他  -或是她
- and bam, and then he... - Or she...
抹掉了枪上指纹  再把枪放到戴尔的手里
wipes the gun clean and puts it into Dale's hand.
他醒来后  慌了神  于是就跑了
He wakes up, he panics, he runs.
与此同时  我们的凶手
All the while, our killer...
不慌不忙地
bides his time,
一直等到有人发现了尸体
waiting until the body is discovered
-他才开始  -或是她
- before he makes his... - Or her...
逃跑  先生们  帮我一下好吗
escape. Gentlemen, would you?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
床垫底部的血迹
The bloodstain on the bottom of the mattress
一直滴到了地毯上
dripped down onto the carpet.
可是中间却没有血迹滴落的痕迹
There's no drip marks in the middle.
借你的手电用一下好吗
Your light?
有指纹
Fingerprints.
有人在这儿待过
Someone was here.
看来这就是凶手的藏身之地
Looks like they found a killer hiding place.
怎么会有人在床底下躲几个小时
Hiding under a bed for hours
看着自己射杀的女孩因流血过多而死
while the girl you just shot bleeds out?
穷凶极恶之徒才能干得出这种事
You gotta be one sick bastard to do something like that.
他也挺聪明的
It's actually pretty clever.
杀了人
You commit a murder
还嫁祸给一个无辜的人
and frame an innocent man all at the same time.
自己却逃脱法律制裁
And then you get away with it
因为警察以为自己已经抓到了凶手
because the police already think they have their killer
所以就没人再去注意他了
and no one's looking for you.
米奇·扬希  他是戴尔的乐队成员
Mitch Yancey. That's Dale's bandmate.
咱们走
Let's go.
莱恩
Ryan.
去那边
Let's go.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我不认为
I don't even think --
放下枪
Put your gun down!
凯特
Kate!
把枪放下
I said put it down!
你只需要
Just...
放我走就行  我只有这点要求
let me walk outta here, okay? That's all I want.
不许  不许
Don't...don't...
不许动  米奇
Don't move, Mitch!
我会开枪的  我发誓
I'll shoot you. I swear.
别慌  凯特
Take it easy, Kate.
你放我走吧
I just need you to let me go.
别慌  你没问题的
Take it easy. You've got this.
你行的
You've got this.
放下枪然后退后  退后
Put it down and stay back. Stay back.
你别逼我  米奇
You don't want to do this, Mitch...
别逼我开枪
because I will have to put you down.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
马上把枪放下
Put that gun down, now.
转过身去  把手放在头上
Turn around. Hands behind your head.
米奇·扬希  你被捕了
Mitch Yancey, you're under arrest.
原来米奇
Turns out Mitch
已经跟索亚秘密交往了一年
had been seeing Sonya secretly for a year,
与此同时索亚还是戴尔的女朋友
all the time she was with Dale.
米奇坚持要她离开戴尔
Mitch insisted that she leave Dale,
可索亚却离开了他
but instead, she broke it off with him.
于是米奇就想出这么一招来干掉他们两个
So this was Mitch's plan to take care of them both.
他知道索亚的安保密码
He knew Sonya's security code,
但是为了嫁祸给戴尔  他知道他不能
but to frame Dale, he knew that the system couldn't record
让系统记录下谋杀发生的时间区内
anyone else entering or exiting the apartment
有人进出公寓
around the time of the murder.
于是他用之前偷来的钥匙
So he used a key that he'd stolen to slip in
在那天早些时候潜入公寓
hours earlier in the day.
好吧  把索亚的男朋友放了
All right. Cut the boyfriend loose.
我去给媒体做简报  让他们知道凶手认罪了
I'll brief the press and let them know we have a confession.
感觉怎么样
So how's it feel?
还不够
It's not enough.
但是
But it's...
就现阶段来讲  够了
enough for now.
谢谢你当时挺我
Thank you for having my back in there.
谁让咱俩是搭档呢
That's what partners are for.
对了  还有
Oh, and hey...
我们会找到办法的
we'll figure it out.
你总有一天会卸下心防的
That wall inside won't be there forever.
你说得没错
You're right.
我是该成熟点
I do need to grow up.
正是因为如此  我才努力做着现在的一切
And that's why I'm doing what I'm doing.
所有这一切都是因我而起
Everything that's happened happened because of me.
我需要陪着她一起度过难关
And I need to be there for her.
这是我欠她的
I owe her that.
她让你感到快乐吗
Does she make you happy?
是的
Yeah, she does.
这就足够了吗
Is it enough?
就目前来说  足够了
It's enough for now.
好吧
Okay.
爸
Dad.
别熟过头了  好吗
Don't grow up too much, okay?
我怎么可能熟过头啊
It's me we're talking about.
看到我回到这儿  你可能有点惊讶吧
You're probably surprised to see me back here.
我想大多数警察在通过了心理评估以后
I bet most cops never come back
都永远不会再回来了
after they pass their psych eval.
每个人的情况都不同
Everyone's different.
你有什么困扰
What's on your mind?
我都不知道该从哪说起
I don't even know where to start.
那我们就从枪击案开始吧
Well, why don't we start with the shooting?
你想起什么来了吗
Is any of it coming back to you?
我之前说我不记得
I lied....
是骗人的
before.
那你到底记得什么
What do you remember?
我记得当时发生的一切
I remember everything.